Hi friends, Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance has their Nishchit Ayush plan
in which you pay the premium only for a certain period of time
.  Then you can get a lifetime
guaranteed income every year
.  This is a savings and life
insurance plan.  This is a non-
linked non-participating
individual savings life insurance
plan.  It should not be linked to the stock market
.  We don't get any
bonuses from this.  But all the returns we receive are
guaranteed every year
.  There are five types of
income options in this.
We have to choose one of them and
pay the premium accordingly.  In this,
the first level is income with lump sum
benefit, in which we not only
get returns every year, but
also get the maturity amount in the end.
Next second is the level income with
enhanced lump sum benefit.  In this too, not only do we
get returns every year, but
we also get a slightly higher maturity amount in the end.  The third is
Increased Income with Lump Sum Benefit, in
which the
returns we receive increase by 5% every five years.
Similarly, we also get the maturity amount in the last month
.  The next fourth level is Level
Income with Return of Premium
Benefit, in which we not only
get returns every year, but also receive a
return of the entire premium amount we have paid in the end
.  Five income-
only benefits are provided to us in the form of annual
returns.
But there is no maturity benefit.
Next, there are two types of options
.  One is long-term income and
two is whole life income. Long-term
income means that returns will continue for as long as you have the policy
.  Whole life
income means that you can
receive returns for a lifetime, even up to 100 years
.  You will also need to select whether
you want long-term income or
lifetime income from the five options above
.
Accordingly, we are provided with returns every year
.  Next, if
you want to take this policy, the minimum age limit is
30 days, the maximum age limit is 55
years, and the minimum maturity age is
18 years. The maximum maturity
age is 85 years for long-term income and
100 years for whole life income.
Next, in this, we can select the policy term from the
first four options mentioned above,
between 15 and 40 years, and
we can get returns accordingly.  If we
select the same Old Life Income,
we will get returns even for 100 years
.  Next,
we have to select one of the premium payment terms, 6, 8, 10, or 12 years, and pay the premium
.  This way we
only pay the premium for a short period of time.  Then,
we will receive returns in all the years of the policy term
.  Next,
although the fifth income option is Income Only
Benefit, the premium payment
terms remain the same: 6, 8, 10, 12
years, but the policy term is
only from the 25th year to 40 years
.  Next, if the minimum amount is issued, you will have to
take out insurance of 21,10,000.  Similarly, you can reach the maximum and
take any amount without any limit.
Next, the minimum premium for the
first four options is 30,000 annually
.  The fifth option is
for only benefit, but
if they are less than 45 years old,
they will have to pay 50,000 rupees annually, and if they are more than 45 years old, they will have to
pay 1 lakh rupees annually.
Next Premium Payment Mode: In this mode, the
premium can be
paid annually, half-yearly, quarterly, monthly
.  Next,
before you take out a policy, you will be required to
compulsorily choose between these three options based on your future financial needs
.  First, you need to
consider whether you want long-term income or lifetime income
.  Second, you will have to
choose one of these five income options, whichever you prefer.
Accordingly,
we receive regular returns every year
.  The next third is that this deferment
period is five years.   Suppose
we want returns only after we buy the policy
.  No, if I want
returns after three years or five years,
we won't get any returns in these first three years.
Returns will come later.  But by adjusting the amount
we should have received in these first three years for
all the remaining years,
we end up receiving 60,000 instead of 50,000
.  If you look at this table, if you set the
premium payment terms to 12
years and the policy term to 40
years, and do not
set the deferment period, you will
get 38.50 from the start.  40
years from the same first year, but
42,300 because that amount is
adjusted for all the remaining years,
so the amount increases.
From the second year onwards, it will be 45,300, from the third year onwards, it will be
48,800, from the fourth year onwards, it will be
52,400, and from the fifth year onwards, it will be 57,200. In this
way, the amount for us will keep increasing
.  But the final
amount we get will be the same.
By adjusting this amount for the remaining years, the
final amount we get will be the same
.  This way we have to choose a deferment period
.  We need to first decide whether
we want the next death benefit to be seven
times the premium we pay or
10 times
.
We can take whatever death benefit amount we receive in the event of any risk occurring next, over a five-year time period.
We can choose whether we want it monthly or yearly.  Suppose we
get a death benefit amount of Rs. 10 lakhs and we want
to take it every month for five years, then we will be given Rs.
18,550 every month for 60 months with an interest of 4.5% to 5%
.  If we
look at it that way, we get a total of 11,13,000
.  If we want to
take it annually, it will be given at the rate of 2,18,000 for five
years.  Thus, the
total amount will come to 10,90,000 in five years
.  The next survival
benefit is the
returns we get every year.  These
returns are similar for
those who have invested the death benefit 10 times, but there is
a slight variation for those who have invested it seven times
.  If we look at this table,
suppose a
person who is 30 years old and is paying an annual premium of Rs 1 lakh for a policy term of 15 years,
he will get
21.10% from the first year, i.e. 21,100, for 15
years.  If you invest the same for 20
years, you will get 27.05 05, which is
27.50. If
you invest for 25 years, you will get
32.50. If you
invest for 30 years, you will get 35,800. If you invest for 35 years, you will get 35,850. If
you invest for 40 years, you will get 36.50.  If the
same whole life is 100 minus his
age of 30 years, then the remaining 70
years will also yield 100
years of returns of 36,450.
Thus, this percentage varies slightly depending on our age and the policy term we take out
.  Next Maturity
Benefit This maturity benefit is
provided to us as per the Guaranteed Annuity Benefit Factor.
This can range from 60 to 200% depending on the premium payment terms and policy term we pay
.  This means that if
the percentage in Sapoja JBL is 70%, then 10
lakhs * 70% = 7 lakhs, and then another 7
lakhs, a total of 14 lakhs, will come to us as maturity
benefit.  There are
five types of riders in Next Riders
.  First, the Extended
Death Benefit Rider assumes that if we invest Rs 10 lakh
as insurance and Rs 5 lakh as rider, then if
any risk
occurs to us, we will be paid Rs 10 lakh insurance plus Rs 5
lakh rider amount, totaling Rs 15 lakh
.  Next Critical
Illness Rider: In the event of a heart attack,
cancer, or other illness, the
rider amount plus the lump sum will be paid to the person if they survive for 30 days after the incident
.
Three surgical care riders provide a
certain amount for any minor operations that are performed
.   The
next fourth is the Hospital Care Rider, which allows
us to climb the payment without a bill if we suffer a fever or any other injury
.  Five Premium
Viewer Riders: In this, if the policyholder takes out a policy for minor children and the
risk occurs,
all remaining premiums are waived and the policy continues
.  Next, I will explain the
five options given to us
clearly with one-by-one examples
.  First, let's assume that a 40-year-old person with a level income with lump
sum benefit
pays a premium of one lakh rupees every year for 10 years
.  If the policy term is 40
years and he has not
invested any deferment period, then if the zero
guaranteed bonus benefit factor is
70%, he will get 35,900 every year for
40 years, which is 14,36,000
.
Similarly, the maturity benefit
under the last term is 70%, so 10 lakhs * 70% = 7
lakhs plus another 7 lakhs, a total of 14
lakhs, will come to him upon maturity.
Looking at it this way, he will receive a total benefit of
28,36,000.  If
he receives returns for 14 years and
then faces any risk, the
returns paid to him till then will be
35,900*4
years = 5,2,600
next death benefit and he
is paying an annual premium of Rs 1 lakh.
Therefore, 10 times 10 lakhs or
105% i.e. 10,50,000, whichever is
higher, will be given.
Next, let's say a
40-year-old person
pays an annual premium of Rs 1 lakh and
has a premium payment term of 10 years, so the policy term is 40
years.  He didn't specify
what the definite period zero means.   If the
guaranteed annuity benefit factor is
100%, then
from the first year onwards, he will receive 34,000 at a rate of
34*40 years, which is 13 lakh 60,000
in returns.  Since the
guaranteed lump sum benefit factor under the 40th year maturity is
100%,
the insurance taken by him is 10 lakhs * 100% 10 lakhs
plus another 10 lakhs, a total of 20 lakhs will be available
under maturity.  Thus, the
total amount he received was
20 lakhs on maturity plus
136,000 returns, totaling 33,60,000.   If
he faces any risk in the 15th year, the
returns he gets in these 14 years are 34,000* 14 years
4,76,000 and the
death benefit
he gets in 15 years is 1 lakh rupees.
So, if we look at it 10 times 10 lakhs or 1.5%, then
10,50,000, whichever is
higher, will be given.
Thus, he will get a death benefit of Rs. 10,50,000
.  Next, the third of these five
options is Increased Income
with Lump Sum Benefit. If a 40-year-old
person pays a premium of Rs 1 lakh,
has a premium payment term of 10 years, and a policy term of 40
years, has a deferment
period of zero, a guaranteed lump sum benefit
factor of 70%, and so on,
he will receive Rs 33,450 every year for
five years.   It will increase by
5% for the next five years to
₹35,123, and then
again five years later to ₹
36,795, and
so on every five years
.  Thus, the total amount received by him
comes to 15,72,150
.  The
insurance he took under maturity for his next 40th year is 10
lakhs, so 10 lakhs * 70% 7 lakhs
plus another 7 lakhs, a total of 14 lakhs
comes under maturity.  Thus, the
total benefit he received at the end of the policy
was 14 lakhs minus 15,72,150,
total 29,72,150. If
he
had a risk in the 15th year, he would have received a return of 13,450
* 5 years plus 35,123 *
5 years plus 36,795 * 4 years
plus 4,90,43
.
In addition, the death benefit came in at
10,50,000, for a total
return of 15,40,43.  Next, the
fourth of these five options is Level
Income with Returned Premium Benefit, in
which the annual premium is one lakh
rupees, the premium payment terms are
10 years, the policy term is 40
years, the deferment period is zero, the
guaranteed lump sum benefit factor is
50%. Thus, he gets 37,900 * 40
years = 15,16,000
.  Similarly,
for a 10 lakh insurance policy under maturity, 50% of 5 lakhs plus
another 5 lakhs, a total of 10 lakhs, was
received under maturity.  In this way, the total
benefit came to 2516000.
Next, if he
had a risk in the 15th year, he would have received 37,900*4
years, or 530,600
.  In addition, a
total of Rs 10,50,000 was returned under the 15th year death benefit, totaling
Rs 15,80,600
.  This policy will close there
.  Next, out of these five options, the
last one is the Income Only Benefit, in which the
annual premium is one lakh rupees, the
premium payment terms are 10
years, the policy term is 40
years, the deferment period is zero, and if
you look at it this way, from the first year,
he will get a return of 43,750 * 40 years, or 17,50,000
.  Since there is no maturity in this fifth option, the
death benefit in this is
given at times the premium we pay, i.e. 7 lakhs
.  In case he has a risk in the 15th year, the
returns paid till then will be 43,750
* 14 years, total 6,12,500
plus death benefit. The premium he pays will be
paid 105 times, whichever is higher
.  If you look at it that way,
10,50,000 will come under his death benefit
.
If we look at the total benefit he received, he received 10,50,000 plus
6,12,500, totaling 16,62,500
rupees.
This policy will close there.  You can
also get a loan of up to 80% of the surrender value after the next loan period of one year
.  The next tax benefit
is that you
can get a tax deduction of up to 1.5 lakhs under Section 80C.
Under Section 10, we
can get the maturity or death benefit tax-free.
After one year of the next surrender value, we can
surrender the policy and
get the amount back.  Friends, this is the complete details of Aditya
Birla Sun Life Insurance's
Nishchit Ayush Plan. If
you like this video, please
like it and share it with everyone if you find it useful.
Thank you.  Um